EUGENIO MARINETTO PHD

Senior Cloud Data Scientist

eugeniomarinetto@gmail.com

Tel. +34 608 212 349 Birth. 24 Mar. 1986

SUMMARY

Senior Data Scientist with more than **9 years of experience**. I solve business problems by means of machine learning, deep learning or statistical data analysis techniques.

I am able to manage data-based projects through analysis, designing and developing cloud solutions to add business value.

I do **enjoy communicating** results in an easy and accessible way to any public because I believe that business teams must understand what mathematical models are doing for their business.

EDUCATION

PhD Biomedical Engineering
 2012 - 2017

Universidad Carlos III de Madrid Computer Guided Surgery, Surgical Tracking, Medical Imaging, Image Processing, Medical Software, Radiotherapy.

Postgraduate Biomedical Eng.
 2009 - 2010

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid Bio-electronics, Medical devices, Medical Imaging.

Master Degree TelecomunicationEngineering

2004 - 2009

Universidad de Granada Signal and Image Processing, Telecomunications systems managements, Electronics, Computer Networks.

COMPLEMENTARY COURSES

- Machine Learning on AWS
 AWS Solutions Training 2019
- Math for Machine Learning
 AWS Solutions Training 2019
- The Elements of Data Science
 AWS Solutions Training 2019
- The Ultimate Hands-On Hadoop
 Udemy 2019

EXPERIENCE

Technical Lead on Artificial Intelligence

CAF Digital Services Madrid \cdot Spain Design and cloud productivization of Artificial Intelligence Solutions. Team leader Al. Design Al strategy and Cloud Solutions

Postgraduate Professor

2019 - Present

Universidad Isabel I Burgos · Spain
Big Data, GDPR, Advance programming and Research

Senior Data Scientist

2018 - 2019 BBVA Next Technologies 2017 - 2018 Strategy BiG Data

Madrid · Spair

Design and development of Machine Learning Models for Business. Cloud application development. Design and cloud productivization of Artificial Intelligence Solutions on AWS and Microsoft Azure

• Bioengineering Research Scientist

Johns Hopkins University - Baltimore· MD
U. Carlos III de Madrid - Madrid · Spain
Image Guided Surgery Applications, Big Data Analysis
& Machine Learning, Software developer.

PERTINENT INFO

- Author of
 - · 12 Scientific Articles
 - · 10 Conference Contributions
- Research experience on several scientific projects
- Teaching experience on graduateand postgraduate
- Machine Learning
 - Coursera 2018
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect
 Linux Academy 2018
- Visual ThinkingBBVA Next 2018
- Azure Data Scientist Learning Path
 Azure learn docs.microsoft.com/es-es/users/emarinetto



Α

Up-to-date algorithms and models. Bayesian network. Interpretability ML, Neural Networks, Reinforcement Learning

Business Ingelligence PowerBi, Google Data

Studio, Spotfire

Cloud

AWS SageMaker, AWS Athena, Serverless, Azure & AWS Databricks, Delta Lake, Terraform

Hadoop Echosystem Spark, Pig, Kafka, Databricks, PySpark, SparkStreaming

Python Expert level

Docker Create and deploy

Data Bases SQL, MSSQL, Mongo, Dynamo, Postgre

app.pluralsight.com/profile/nenetto

SOFT SKILLS

Communication
Networking
Clear and Informative
Presentations

Management Manage project and teams. Agile & Scrum

Ethical work
Transparency and fairness

Teaching Wide experience

****** LANGUAGES

English
 Full Professional Proficiency

Japanese Elementary Proficiency

Spanish Native